# Will Epperson

I'm a Ph.D. student in the HCII at CMU advised by Adam Perer and Dominik Moritz.

My research interests lie in **developing ways to make complex systems easier to use and understand for non-experts**. Specifically, I am working to enable *interpretable Machine Learning*, often through *interactive visualizations*. I'm also interested in how machine learning can be applied to the medical domain to help both doctors and patient experiences.

willepperson.com

■ willepp@cmu.edu

CV PDF

@w\_epperson

@willeppy

Google Scholar

LinkedIn

### Education

August 2020 - Present

#### Ph.D. in Human Computer Interaction

Carnegie Mellon University

Advisor: Dominik Moritz, Co-advisor: Adam Perer

August 2016 - May 2020

#### **B.S. in Computer Science**

Georgia Institute of Technology

GPA: 4.0, Summa Cum Laude, threads in Intelligence and Modeling/Simulation

### **Publications**

#### FairVis: Visual Analytics for Discovering Intersectional Bias in Machine Learning

Angel Cabrera, Will Epperson, Fred Hohman, Minsuk Kahng, Jamie Morgenstern, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST). Vancouver, Canada, 2019.

Ø Project ▶ Demo PDF Blog ■ Recording Slides Code BibTeX

### **RECAST: Interactive Auditing of Automatic Toxicity Detection Models**

Austin P. Wright, Omar Shaikh, Haekyu Park, Will Epperson, Muhammed Ahmed, Stephane Pinel, Diyi Yang, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

The eighth International Workshop of Chinese CHI. 2020.

### Talks

**FairVis** 

May 2019

**IEEE Visualization Conference** 

### **Honors and Awards**

2019

PURA: President's Undergraduate Research Award \$1500 research grant to continue work on FairVis project

2016

Stamps President's Scholarship

Full ride scholarship given to 40 incoming freshman at Georgia Tech

### Research Experience

January 2019 - May 2020

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Undergraduate Researcher, Polo Club of Data Science

Advisor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Member of the Polo Club of Data Science working on novel data visulizations to find fairness issues in Machine Learning models

January 2018 - May 2019

#### Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Undergraduate Researcher, Automated Algorithm Design

Advisor: Jason Zutty, Greg Rohling

Worked on EMADE algorithm design engine to implement sentiment analysis pipeline to analyze news articles to aid in predicting stock price movements using genetic algorithms. Led project to visualize the genetic algorithm evolution process.

## **Industry Experience**

Summer 2019

**Point72 Asset Management**, New York, NY *Data Analytics Intern, Market Intelligence Group* 

Mentor: Trevor Rempel

Worked as Data Scientist in alternative data space to clean, model, and understand large datasets

Summer 2018

Ultimate Software, Weston, FL

Software Development Intern, Innovation Strategies Team

Mentor: Joseph Cutrono

Designed and developed Slack app to integrate with the UltiPro HR management tool. App published to Slack app store.

### **Teaching**

August 2017 - December 2018

#### **Undergraduate Teaching Assistant**

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Intro to Database Systems (CS 4400), Instructor: Monica Sweat Designed projects, held office hours and graded for relational databases class.

### **Leadership & Activities**

January 2019 - May 2020

#### **Student Ambassador**

Georgia Institute of Technology Alumni Association

Serve as official representative of the Institute at events/tours for alumni, prospective students, and special guests.

January 2018 - May 2019

#### **Executive Board Member -- Threads Co-chair**

Stamps Scholars National Convention 2019

Executive board member of Stamps Scholars National Convention, a 3-day conference with over 700 student attendees. Responsible for 20-person committee that plans and coordinates the different content threads of the convention.